{"tossups": [{"question": "Eugene Dennis was one of the first eleven of these people convicted of violating the Smith Act. A namesake \u201cControl Act\u201d outlawed formal organizations of these people, which had previously been forced to register with the Justice Department under the (*) McCarran Act. Howard Hughes bought and shut down RKO Studios to remove and \u201cblacklist\u201d some of these people. The Hollywood Ten was a group of these people involved in the film industry, while a namesake \u201cLoyalty Program\u201d targeted these people in the federal government. For 10 points, name these people targeted by Joseph McCarthy in the Second Red Scare.", "answer": "communists in the United States (prompt on socialists; accept any answers indicating that a person was a communist, communist sympathizer, or member of the Communist Party of the United States of America) ", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>communists in the United States</u></b>", "acceptable": ["communists in the United States"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "prompt on socialists; accept any answers indicating that a person was a communist, communist sympathizer, or member of the Communist Party of the United States of America"}, {"question": "This author wrote about two people in a debate who state \u201cI bet that is also a parable\u201d and \u201cin parable you have lost.\u201d In a brief parable, this author describes a messenger\u2019s challenge of leaving the imperial palace and the capital city, while in another parable, a man bribes a doorkeeper who still will not let him through a gate. This author of \u201cOn Parables\u201d and \u201cAn (*) Imperial Message\u201d included \u201cBefore the Law\u201d in a work in which a character is put on trial and executed \u201clike a dog\u201d for an unnamed crime. For 10 points, name this author who wrote about Josef K. in The Trial and Gregor Samsa turning into an insect in The Metamorphosis.", "answer": "Franz Kafka ", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Franz <b><u>Kafka</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Franz Kafka"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During this conflict, the Mimi and Toutou [too-too] were brought by train and road to take control of Lake Tanganyika, and Maximilian von Spee was killed at the Battle of the Falkland Islands. The Breslau and Goeben were chased across the Mediterranean before they were gifted to the (*) Ottoman Empire during this conflict. During a battle in this conflict, Admiral John Jellicoe crossed the T of a German fleet. The Battle of Jutland allowed the blockade of Germany to continue in, for 10 points, what conflict in which unrestricted submarine warfare resulted in the sinking of the Lusitania?", "answer": "World War I (or WWI) ", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>World War I</u></b>", "acceptable": ["World War I"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or WWI"}, {"question": "In environmental chemistry, a form of this quantity is used in conjunction with the non-ideality factor gamma and the mole fraction to represent fugacity and calculate the chemical potential of a liquid mixture. The log of one form of this quantity is related to temperature and the constants A, B, and C by the (*) Antoine Equation. Raoult\u2019s Law is used to find one form of this quantity, which is higher for more volatile substances. For any isobaric process, this quantity times volume is equal to n times R times T. For 10 points, name this measure of force per unit area, a quantity often given in bars or atmospheres. ", "answer": "vapor pressure (accept air pressure) ", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>vapor pressure</u></b>", "acceptable": ["vapor pressure"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept air pressure"}, {"question": "This story was borrowed from the Giovanni Boccaccio epic Teseida and inspired the Shakespeare play The Two Noble Kinsmen. Prayers to Diana, Mars, and Venus are all answered in the climactic scene of this story. In this story, two men are found unconscious after a battle and imprisoned, after which they see a beautiful woman in a garden. (*) Emily, the daughter of the Athenian Duke Theseus, is offered to the winner of a tournament contested by Arcite [ahr-SEE-tuh] and Palamon in this story, which follows the Prologue and precedes the Miller\u2019s Tale. For 10 points, name this Canterbury Tale told by a character who accompanies the Squire.", "answer": "\u201cThe Knight\u2019s Tale\u201d ", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>\u201cThe Knight\u2019s Tale\u201d</u></b>", "acceptable": ["\u201cThe Knight\u2019s Tale\u201d"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to John Rawls\u2019s A Theory of Justice, the creation of this construct occurs behind a \u201cveil of ignorance\u201d and emerges from the \u201coriginal position.\u201d Another idea of this construct based it on the \u201csupreme direction of the general will\u201d and according to (*) Leviathan, the establishment of this construct ends the \u201cwar of all against all\u201d caused by the \u201cstate of nature.\u201d \u201cMan is born free, and everywhere, he is in chains,\u201d was written by Jean-Jacques Rousseau in a book titled for, for 10 points, what agreement under which freedoms are forfeited in exchange for protection by a government?", "answer": "the social contract (accept On the Social Contract; prompt on government and similar answers) ", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the social contract</u></b>", "acceptable": ["the social contract"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept On the Social Contract; prompt on government and similar answers"}, {"question": "When he was dying of starvation, this mythical figure was told to bathe in the Pactolus river. This character received a gift after entertaining the satyr Silenus before bringing him back to Dionysus, and is often referred to as the adopted child of Gordias and Cybele [SIB-a-lee]. After siding with Pan in a (*) music contest with Apollo, this figure was given the ears of a donkey, and this Phrygian king lost his desire for wealth following a period in which all his food and drink, and possibly his daughter, turned to gold. For 10 points, name this figure who possessed the golden touch.", "answer": "King Midas of Phrygia ", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "King Midas of <b><u>Phrygia</u></b>", "acceptable": ["King Midas of Phrygia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An algebraic number field is an extension of this group of numbers, which is also the smallest field with characteristic zero. The p-adic numbers are another extension of this set, which is not locally compact. Lambert proved that if n is one of these numbers e to the power of n is not, while Cantor used a (*) diagonalization proof to show that this set is countable. Numbers with repeating or finite decimals belong to this set. The capital letter Q represents the set of, for 10 points, what numbers that can be represented as fractions of two integers, which are contrasted with irrational numbers?", "answer": "rational numbers (or rationals; accept Q before mention) ", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>rational numbers</u></b>", "acceptable": ["rational numbers"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or rationals; accept Q before mention"}, {"question": "One player in this league claimed to have chronic Lyme disease and to have taken 64 pills a day in \u201cAn Open Letter About My Health,\u201d written in The Players\u2019 Tribune after this league said that that player would not be paid if they sat out the 2020 season. Another player from this league has taken time off to advocate for criminal (*) justice reform, including the release of their now-husband Jonathan Irons. Before becoming a coach for the San Antonio Spurs, Becky Hammon played for the San Antonio Stars in this league, whose 2019 championship was won by the Washington Mystics. For 10 points, name this professional basketball league.", "answer": "Women\u2019s National Basketball Association (or WNBA) ", "subcategory": "Trash", "category": "Trash", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Women\u2019s National Basketball Association</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Women\u2019s National Basketball Association"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or WNBA"}, {"question": "In one film from this non-American country, a snack vendor\u2019s daughter is kidnapped by a monster formed after formaldehyde is dumped into a river. The Animal Liberation Front and Mija [MEE-ja] attempt to rescue a super-pig in a Netflix film from this country. Another film from this country depicts an (*) impoverished family living in a semi-basement apartment while obtaining jobs from a wealthier family. That film from this country was the first foreign film to win the Academy Award for Best Picture. For 10 points, name this home country of Bong Joon-ho, the director of The Host, Okja, and Parasite.", "answer": "South Korea (accept Republic of Korea; prompt on Korea but do not accept or prompt on \u201cDemocratic People\u2019s Republic of Korea\u201d) ", "subcategory": "Other Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "South <b><u>Korea</u></b>", "acceptable": ["South Korea"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept Republic of Korea; prompt on Korea but do not accept or prompt on \u201cDemocratic People\u2019s Republic of Korea\u201d"}, {"question": "A siege of a weapons depository at Hull marked the beginning of this conflict, during which the \u201cIronsides\u201d were an elite cavalry unit. One battle in this conflict was lost by the Earl of Manchester and Lord Fairfax following the Siege of (*) York, and Irish involvement in this conflict ended after massacres at Wexford and Drogheda. During this conflict, the Long Parliament was shrunk into the Rump Parliament, which tried Charles I for treason. The New Model Army was formed by Oliver Cromwell during, for 10 points, what conflict that pitted the Parliamentarians against the Royalists?", "answer": "English Civil Wars ", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>English Civil Wars</u></b>", "acceptable": ["English Civil Wars"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The PI curve graphs the performance of this process, rising as you move along the x-axis until a namesake \u201creaction center\u201d is damaged in \u201cinhibition\u201d caused by high intensity. Malic acid is stored in vacuoles as part of one form of this larger process, while in another form of this larger process oxalo\u2022acetate is released in (*) bundle sheath cells after it is formed in mesophyll cells. In the most common form of this process, NADP+ is reduced to NADPH, and it takes place across the thylakoid membrane of chloroplast organelles. CAM, C4, and the Calvin Cycle are alternate forms of, for 10 points, what process, in which ATP is produced from sunlight?", "answer": "photosynthesis ", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>photosynthesis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["photosynthesis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A nude woman wears a lampshade on her head and a nude man covers himself with a tootsie pop in a collage from this movement. A drowning woman is depicted saying \u201cI\u2019d rather sink than call Brad for help\u201d in one work from this movement, while in another work by the same artist, the title character covers his mouth in laughter as a (*) duck catches itself with a fishing rod. That work is the painting Look, Mickey! Richard Hamilton is an artist from this movement, whose pioneers included an artist who produced silkscreens of Marilyn Monroe in \u201cThe Factory.\u201d For 10 points, name this movement whose artists included Roy Lichtenstein and Andy Warhol.", "answer": "Pop Art ", "subcategory": "Painting", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Pop Art</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Pop Art"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one novel set in this country, the title character refuses to work and starves an entire town after the death of Susanna San Juan. Juan Preciado meets several ghostly characters in the town of Comala in that novel from this country. Another author from this country included \u201cThe Dialectic of Solitude\u201d and \u201cThe Conquest and (*) Colonialism\u201d in a set of essays discussing this country\u2019s separate Spanish and indigenous cultures. Juan Rulfo, the author of Pedro P\u00e1ramo [PAH-ra-mo], is from this country, as is the author of The Labyrinth of Solitude. For 10 points, \u201cSunstone,\u201d a 584-line poem inspired by the Aztec calendar, was written by Octavio Paz, an author from what country?", "answer": "Mexico (or United Mexican States) ", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mexico</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Mexico"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or United Mexican States"}, {"question": "A formula showing that parabolic PDEs can be expressed as a sum is named for this scientist and Marc Kac. This scientist modeled weak decay with Murray Gell-Mann and demonstrated that weakness of O-rings in cold weather caused the (*) Challenger Disaster. This scientist discussed nanoscale machines in the lecture \u201cThere\u2019s Plenty of Room at the Bottom\u201d and delivered a namesake set of \u201cLectures on Physics\u201d at Caltech. For 10 points, name this physicist who helped develop quantum electrodynamics and names a type of diagram visualizing the behavior of subatomic particles.", "answer": "Richard Feynman ", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Richard Feynman</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Richard Feynman"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Rusumo Falls are near the source of this river, which goes over the Murchison Falls near Lake Kyoga. The Bahr el Ghazal and the Sobat River are two large tributaries of this river, while one of its branches is the site of the Grand Renaissance Dam. As this river flows through its \u201cGreat Bend,\u201d it runs through the Six (*) Cataracts, the northernmost of which is the site of the Aswan Low Dam. The \u201cWhite\u201d and \u201cBlue\u201d branches of this river meet near Khartoum, and its delta stretches from Port Said [sai-EED] to Alexandria. For 10 points, name this longest river in Africa.", "answer": "Nile River (accept White Nile or Blue Nile) ", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Nile River</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Nile River"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept White Nile or Blue Nile"}, {"question": "This character is described as \u201ca great favorite among all the good wives of the village,\u201d but had an \u201caversion to all kinds of profitable labor,\u201d with \u201cragged\u201d children and the \u201cworst-conditioned\u201d farm. This character visits Johnathan Doolittle\u2019s Union Hotel, where he is asked if he voted \u201cFederal or Democrat\u201d and learns that Nicholas Veder had (*) died and Van Bummel was in Congress. This character carries a keg to an amphitheater, where he encounters Henry Hudson\u2019s crew playing ninepins, after ending up high in the Catskills at night. For 10 points, name this title character of a Washington Irving short story, who falls asleep for twenty years.", "answer": "Rip van Winkle (accept either underlined portion) ", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Rip van Winkle</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Rip van Winkle"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "accept either underlined portion"}, {"question": "When performing one piece by this composer, clarinetists open the left-hand tone holes while moving from F to B flat, in a part originally improvised by Ross Gorman. Another piece by this composer introduced the 32-bar progression \u201cRhythm Changes\u201d and was written for the musical Girl Crazy. Four (*) taxi horns were used at the premiere of this composer\u2019s An American in Paris, while another of his compositions premiered at a concert titled An Experiment in Modern Music and opens with a clarinet glissando. For 10 points, name this American composer of \u201cI\u2019ve Got Rhythm\u201d and Rhapsody in Blue.", "answer": "George Gershwin (or Jacob Bruskin Gershowitz) ", "subcategory": "Music", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>George Gershwin</u></b>", "acceptable": ["George Gershwin"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or Jacob Bruskin Gershowitz"}, {"question": "One ruler of this empire imprisoned his father and reneged on a co-rulership pact with his brother during a succession war. That ruler of this empire won the Battle of Samugarh against Dara Shikoh, while another of its leaders created the syncretic religion Din-i-Ilahi and built a capital at (*) Fatehpur Sikri. In the 18th century, the Bengal War and the Carnatic Wars caused this dynasty to lose territory to France and Great Britain. This dynasty overthrew Ibrahim Lodhi at the First Battle of Panipat, which was won by Babur, while the Taj Mahal was built by its leader Shah Jahan. For 10 points, name this Islamic empire of India.", "answer": "Mughal Empire ", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Mughal Empire</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Mughal Empire"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A book with this name includes the Parable of Drawing in the Net and the Parable of the Two Sons. That book with this name begins with the genealogy of Jesus from David and Abraham, and ends with the command to \u201cgo and make disciples of all nations\u201d in the \u201cGreat Commission.\u201d As part of the \u201ctwo-source hypothesis,\u201d a book with this name shares the (*) Q source with Luke. An apostle with this name witnessed the ascension and worked as a tax collector before travelling with Jesus. For 10 points, give this name shared by the first Gospel of the New Testament.", "answer": "Matthew (or the Gospel According to Matthew) ", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Matthew</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Matthew"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": "or the Gospel According to Matthew"}]}